## **Personal Information**

Name:LI ZIQIEmail Address:liziqi\_@hotmail.comGender:MaleCurrent Location:Xiamen, Fujian, China

Birth Year: 1991 Citizenship: Chinese

Online Profile: http://www.linkedin.com/in/liziqi/

Personal Website: https://lizq-github.github.io/Resume-CV/

## **Personal Profile**

Stay Hungry, Stay Foolish - Steve Job

Through the overseas study experience and the multi-nation working experience from the past 2 years, I trained myself to be a highly self-motivated, task-oriented, open-minded and someone who is willing to spend extra to learn new skill-sets to meet the demands of my job.

## **Skills & Abilities**

Language Proficiency English and Chinese (Written & Spoken fluently)

Programming Background Matlab, Java, C++, Python, and Shell

Core Competence Software Development, Team Management,

Team Communication, Self-learning

## **Work Experience**

01.2018-Now Motic China Group Co., Ltd

Software Developer

Worked as a software developer in the Development Department, and mainly handle the following tasks

- Self-learning Matlab, to work on an auto-scope project with Intellectual Ventures Lab - Global Good, handle and in charge the following tasks:
  - Conversion, converting Matlab source code to C++ via tool -Coder and hand-coding (line by line translating from Matlab language to C++ language).
  - Develop automatic scripts for different testing and validation purposes.
  - Integrate the converted code with existing product.
  - Use Git as source code version control tool.
- ➤ Machine Learning, deep learning, convolutional neural network training course with Intellectual Ventures Lab Global Good at Seattle, Washington, USA. The following topics are covered: (March June 2019)
  - Learn the techniques used for data preparation
  - Learn the techniques used for data handling, e.g. augmentation.
  - Learn the usage of different layers, hyper-parameters.

- Learn the methods for regression, clustering.
- Self-learning Deep Learning Tensorflow
  - Use transfer learning and re-training to train an image classifier to classify the types of cells.
  - Use transfer learning and re-training to train an object detection to detect the objects via Nvidia container.
- ➤ Using Android Studio to maintain the Android application
  - Develop new features
  - Bug fixes
  - Brief the new features or fixes to the production line and prepare power point slides to train them to adapt the changes.
  - Use Git as source code version control tool.
- Using Shell Scripting to patch the software on the Linux platform remotely.

In order to ensure the correctness of the patch, the following steps are followed. Firstly, investigating on the bugs, secondly evaluating the workload, thirdly making the patch shell scripting and do a self-test on the patches, lastly provide the patch installation documentation, and assisting the customer with the patching.

08.2017-12.2017 IBM Manufacturing Solutions Pte Ltd.

Intern

Worked as a software developer in the IBM Software Department – Deployment Automation Team, and mainly using Shell Scripting to handle the following tasks:

- Self-learning Jenkins then adopted a new authentication method on IBM Jenkins Server, e.g. LDAP (Lightweight Directory Access Protocol).
- ➤ Self-learning Docker, then work with the docker containers e.g. deploy the Docker containers.
- ➤ Self-learning IBM WAS (WebSphere Application Server) and patching the server.
- > Self-learning IBM BPM (Business Process Manager) and patching the server.
- Self-learning IBM UCD (Urban Code Deployment) and use it as a tool for the deployment automation.
- ➤ Self-learning the software version control GitHub.

05.2017-07.2017 Motic China Group Co. Ltd.

Intern

Worked as a software developer in the Software Development Department. Mainly doing the following tasks:

- ➤ Migrate a Visual Studio 2008 based program to Visual Studio 2013 based program.
- Integrate with Motic protection mechanism, e.g. hardware dongle and software license.
- Integrate with Motic hardware, e.g. the Motic camera series.
- ➤ Get familiar with the migration of the Matlab solution to C++ language based.

08.2016-05.2017 Final Year Project with NTU – Monitor System for the Elderly

The main objective of this project is to develop a monitoring system to keep track of the elderly's motions through multiple sensors, based on the collected data to make a decision whether the elderly needs help or not.

- Data collection, use Arduino Uno R3 board to work with different hardware sensors then send to collected data to the laptop via the radio communication module.
- ➤ Data handling, use Visual Studio to develop required programs:
  - ◆ Client, listen to the radio communication module and handover to the server.
  - ◆ Server, store to data from the client to the SQL database and link the web application to access the database.
  - ◆ Web Application, provide the interface for the caregivers to access the collected data via account and password.

08.2015-11.2015 Self-Employment

Project Manager

Gathered a team of five to provide services to a company. E.g. Android,IOS and web page development for their online ticket ordering system which is used for the bus services.

11.2014-06.2015 S&Z Pte Ltd.

Entrepreneur

Join a start-up software company which is launched by a friend from NTU. I played a part as a helper in recruitment and project planning.

Education			
07.2014-12.2017	Nanyang Technological University	Computer Engineering	Degree
03.2011-04.2014	Singapore Polytechnic	Info-Communication & Design	Diploma
08.2007-12.2010	Montfort Secondary School		GCE O Level

Awards	
2012	Singapore Polytechnic - Merit Award - Singapore Technologies Telemedia Prize
2012	Singapore Polytechnic - Director's Honour Roll
2013	Singapore Polytechnic - Merit Award - Hutcabb Prize
2013	Singapore Polytechnic - Director's Honour Roll
2014	Singapore Polytechnic - Merit Award - Singapore Technologies Telemedia Prize
2014	Singapore Polytechnic - Diploma With Merit
2018	Nanyang Technological University – Degree with Honours (Merit)